2014年9月17日
是我们抵达地球的日子
The day we arrived.
我们从一个濒临灭亡的星球逃离
We fled a dying planet.
星  恋
第一季 第一集
我们的飞船迫降在这里
Our ship crash-landed here.
对于我们来说  这应是解放日
For my kind, it was meant to be a day of liberation.
避难日
Refuge.
但是对于地球人来说
But for everyone on Earth...
这却是侵略
it was an invasion.
人类让我们别无选择  只能自我防卫
The humans left us no choice but to defend ourselves.
弹药来袭
Incoming!
人人影视
YYeTs.com
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：冰蓝    Hannah    叉烧包    小花豆    北湾    喃喃
■
时间轴：小萌    贝壳    后期：冰河   校对&监制：非燕
快跑  快跑
快跑
我听从了父亲的吩咐
I did as my father said.
我奋力飞奔
I ran as fast as my legs would carry me,
不知道自己在逃避什么
not understanding what I was running from.
更不确定我在奔向什么
And less sure what I was running to.
国民警卫队继续
National Guardsmen continue
和外星人进行一场流血冲突
to engage in a bloody conflict with the alien species,
他们的飞船坠落在巴吞鲁日外的几公里处
whose ship crashed to Earth several miles from Baton Rouge.
总统宣称进入紧急状态
The president has issued a state of emergency.
而官方人士报告  一些侵略者
While officials report that some of the invaders
已经被包围
have been rounded up,
侵略者袭击  伤亡人数增加
可能有些外星人逃脱了追捕
it's possible some may have eluded capture.
你觉得外星人的计划是什么
What do you think would be the alien plan?
我们该去我母亲家
We should go to my mother's.
道路封锁了
The roads are closed.
而且  去了那边情况也不会好转
And plus, things aren't gonna be any better over there.
尽量放松吧
Just try and relax.
怎么了  爸爸
What's wrong, Daddy?
没事  宝贝
Nothing, baby.
一切都很好
Everything's fine.
别忘了吃药  埃默里
Don't forget to take your medicine, Emery.
好的  爸爸
Okay, Daddy.
刚刚传来的消息  航空航天局的天文学家推断
Just getting word; NASA astronomers have speculated
这艘宇宙飞船的轨道
that the trajectory of the spacecraft
起源于一个名叫奥特里安的遥远的太阳系
originated from a distant solar system called Atria.
不管他们从何而来
Regardless of where they came from,
当地居民和世界领导都很担心其意图
local residents and world leaders are wary of their intentions.
有人吗
Hello?
没事的  没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
你也是外星人  对吧
You're one of them, aren't you?
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
另一方面  如果
If, on the other hand,
他们的目标实为征服并占领地球
their goal was actual occupation and conquest,
那他们可能会优先考虑那些...
then they would probably have to prioritize anything...
没事的
It's okay.
你看起来不像个怪物
You don't look like a monster.
你今晚可以待在这里
You can stay here tonight.
我早晨再来看你
I'll come see you in the morning.
别出声
Be very quiet.
很好吃  对吧
It's good, isn't it?
给  用叉子
Here. Use the fork.
这个叫星星
This one's called star.
从这里穿过
Through here.
从里面穿过
Through the loop.
松开  就是颗星星  你来试试
Let go, it's a star. Here, you try.
B小队1-7
Bravo unit one-seven...
得把你藏起来
We've got to hide you.
他在这里
He's in here!
快上  快上
Go, go, go, go, go!
离她远点
Get away from her!
别伤害他
Don't hurt him!
-快  -不要
- Now! - No!
十年后
十年前  名叫奥特里安人的
It's been ten years since the alien species
外星物种抵达地球
known as the Atrians arrived on Earth,
美国军方将其包围
and the U.S. Military rounded them up
将他们送入一处政府辖区
and put them in a government facility
一直关押到现在
where they remained in lockdown.
今天  在尝试将他们融入社会的争议中
Today, in a controversial effort to integrate them into society,
七名奥特里安青少年会成为马歇尔高中的学生
seven Atrian teens will become students at Marshall High School.
备受争议的取消七名奥特里安
青少年隔离的计划
小朱
Hey, Jules.
埃默里
Hey, Emery.
只有你才能在早上七点展现大汗淋漓的性感
Only you could pull off sweaty sexy at 7:00 A.M.
在马歇尔高中外面  愤怒的抗议者要求
Outside Marshall High, angry protesters demand
马歇尔高中实况
愤怒的抗议仍在继续
奥特里安人继续被关押在他们的隔离区
that the Atrians remain sequestered inside their sector.
该做拉伸运动了  来吧
Time to stretch. Come on.
我的前任病友现在成了我的私人教练
My former hospital buddy's now my personal trainer.
你说过一直想要一个的
You said you always wanted one.
是啊  名字叫费尔南多
Yeah. Named Fernando.
或者特里斯坦
Or Tristan.
他有外国口音  还有腹肌
With an accent and abs.
这些反对消除隔离的拥护者相信奥特里安人
These anti-integration advocates believe the Atrians
抗议者要求了解
奥特里安人隐瞒了什么
也许心怀鬼胎  想把地球变为殖民地
may be hiding a greater plan to colonize Earth.
如果要问我  这整个隔离计划
If you ask me, this whole integration program
只不过是为了分散大家的注意力
is just a distraction from the real issue.
-每个频道都在放这个吗  -对
- Is this on every channel? - Yep.
市民对消除隔离的反应
那艘飞船在整座小镇上投下了阴影
That ship is casting a shadow over this whole town...
市民对消除隔离的反应
疯子们今天都出来了
All the loonies are out today.
真是不得不爱阴谋论者啊
You got to love conspiracy theorists.
有一个人声称奥特里安人
One of them was claiming that the Atrians
在隔离区里种植了一种草药  名叫柏草
grow a medicinal herb inside their Sector called cyper.
能治疗阴谋论者吗
Can it cure conspiracy theorists?
我只是说
I'm just saying.
也许你可以和一个奥特里安人搞好关系
Maybe you could get chummy with one of the Atrians.
拿到一批柏草
Get a batch.
拯救这整所医院
Fix up this whole hospital.
我怎么说的
What did I say?
怀特希尔指挥官
让他们后退
Keep these guys back.
天啊  是你爸爸
Oh, my God, it's your dad.
如你所见  隔离区执法队的雷·怀特希尔指挥官
As you can see, Commander Ray Whitehill of the Sector Enforcement Unit
怀特希尔指挥官
扫描了七名奥特里安人的腕带
scans the wristbands of the Atrian Seven,
这样他们在学校里时  当局就能追踪其位置
allowing authorities to track their location while at school.
他真走运
He's so lucky.
他是为数不多真正可以说
He's, like, one of the few people who can actually say
去过隔离区的人
that they've been inside the Sector.
当然只有你才会认为那是走运
Of course only you would consider that lucky.
七名奥特里安人离开隔离区
那你对今天觉得紧张吗
So, you nervous about today?
当然觉得
Yeah. Sure.
昨晚新闻里的那个人说着
I mean, the guy on the news last night was saying
全世界都会关注马歇尔高中
how the eyes of the world would be on Marshall High.
七名奥特里安人离开隔离区
让你四年后重返学校的第一天
Leave it to you to start your first day back at school after four years
就被全世界关注
in front of the eyes of the world.
向政府施压
...are putting pressure on our government.
媒体没有进行全面报道
The media hasn't covered it thoroughly enough...
真高兴你病情好转了  小埃
I'm really glad you got better, Em.
谢谢你
Thanks.
轮到你了
Now it's your turn.
奥特里安七名青少年正前往马歇尔高中
The Atrian Seven are now headed to Marshall High,
那里的反对者越来越多
where protests continue to grow.
我代表所有特区政府的同事们
I speak for all my colleagues in D.C.
通过将近三年的不断讨论
When I say that after three years of ongoing discussion,
我们很荣幸  终于实现了这个项目
we're very proud to see this program finally come to fruition.
如果这一项目成功的话
A program which, if successful,
可以让所有奥特里安人融入社会
could lead to the integration of all Atrians into society.
我们希望我们不仅能够和平共处
The hope is that we're not just able to peacefully coexist,
还能互相学习
but we also learn from one another.
他们的文化
Their culture alone...
那些歪星人不属于这里
Those Tatties belong with their own kind!
这属于我们的孩子们
Our kids were raised right.
放开我  放开我
Get off of me. Get off of me!
歪星人  滚回家
Tatties, go home!
走吧  咱们四处转转
Come on, let's go around back.
科学实验室里有一些被编号的猴子
In the tech lab are code monkeys.
就好像是这个奇怪的世界
It's kind of like this weird world
被一些什么猴子啦猩猩啦统治了
dominated by chimps and orangutans or whatever--
他们还不知道怎么和人交流
has no idea how to communicate with humans.
如果你看一眼
And if you look discreetly
你两点钟方向  亚洲时尚达人
to your two o'clock: Asian fashionistas.
他们同样的衣服从来不穿两次
They never wear the same thing twice.
看楼上  二楼平台上
And further up the stairs, on the second landing,
是列宁崇拜者
are the Lenin worshipers.
是那个共产主义列宁
The Communist Lenin,
不是披头士的那个
not the Beatle.
你第一节什么课  英语文学吗
What's your first class? English lit?
但愿你没选特克先生的课
I hope you didn't get Mr. Turk.
他会让你读《耸肩的阿特拉斯》
I mean, he'll make you read Atlas Shrugged.
总之一句话
And let's just say
它的课特别沉闷
that it is a total, utter downer.
特别沉闷  小埃
It's a downer, Em,
然后我肯定你没有听我说话
and I'm so sure that you're not even listening to me.
-小埃  -我听着呢
- Em! - Yes, I'm listening.
你刚刚说特别沉闷
You said it's a total and utter downer.
他们来了
They're here.
滚吧
Get out of here!
滚回家
Go home!
滚回家  滚回家
Go home! Go home!
都下车
Everybody off.
好了  跟我来
All right, follow me.
来吧  快点
Let's go. Move it.
排好队  排成一排  肩并肩站好
Line it up, single file, shoulder width.
到这里排好
I want a line right here.
快排好
Line it up.
成一直线
Form a line.
在这儿排  你  站这里
Right here along. You. Right here.
今天还能再疯狂一点吗
I mean, could this day possibly get any more insane?
刚才不就是吗
I think it just did.
我叫格洛丽亚
My name is Gloria.
你们不认识我  但我熟悉你们每个人
You don't know me, but I am well-acquainted with each of you.
[外星语]
没错  泰瑞  我最近是和人上床了
Yes, Teri, I have been laid recently.
并且在马歇尔高中只能说英语
And English is the language of choice here at Marshall High.
你们已经简单学习了礼仪
I know you've been briefed on protocol
通过了MHS入学考试
and passed your MHS entrance exams,
但是我认为有必要讲点规矩
but I think it's necessary to set some ground rules
为了你们的安全着想
for your own safety.
想必你们已经注意到增设的安全设施
I'm sure you've noticed increased security.
我们不希望有任何暴力事件
We don't anticipate any violence,
这些警卫是为了保护你们
but the guards are here for your protection.
和奥特里安人
And the Atrians.
警卫被批准使用震慑枪
The guards have been authorized to use their temblor guns
如果你们走出警戒线
if you step out of line.
你们只能离开隔离区去上学
You are only permitted to leave the Sector for school.
宵禁仍然存在
Curfew still stands.
每晚必须在10点前回去
Back in your pods by 10:00 p.m. every night.
在学校里面  他们和你们一样
Behind the walls of this school, they're just like you.
他们也是学生
They're students.
你们是实验对象
You're test subjects.
至少现在是
At least for the time being.
但是总有一天  你们可以从这里毕业
But one day, you could be graduating.
去上大学  或者工作
Heading off to college or out in the work force.
想一下  这个项目有可能成功
Imagine the possibilities if this program is a success.
但是这很不容易
But it won't be easy.
很多人都希望你们会失败
A lot of people are hoping you fail.
他们认为你们就是来毁灭我们的
They think your race has come here to destroy us.
你们要证明他们说错了
It's up to you to prove them wrong.
真希望咱们是那种拿着镭射枪的外星人
Wish we were the kind of aliens who carried ray guns.
还记得咱们在隔离区学校的第一天吗
Remember our first day at the Sector School?
你们也不喜欢那里
You guys hated it there, too.
在那咱们至少不用担心震慑枪
At least we didn't have to worry about temblor guns pointed at our heads.
或者更糟的  合唱团
Or worse. Glee club.
咱们的柜子还被做了标记
They tagged our lockers.
右手
Right.
你得用右手按
You got to use your right hand.
对了
Yes.
我发誓我用高科技产品不经常这么差劲的
I swear I'm not usually this technologically inept.
这没什么
It's okay.
你第一天表现得不错
You get a pass on your first day.
你从哪转来的
Where you transferring from?
我不是转学来的
Oh, nowhere.
我只是过去四年
I've just been out.
一直在外面
For the last four years.
我去年从纽霍尔转来的
I transferred last year from Newhall.
我也没参加迎新会什么的
And I'm not on the welcoming committee or anything,
但我对这挺熟的  如果你需要什么帮忙
but I know my way around, so if you need anything...
谢谢你
Thanks.
教我用手指
For the finger tip.
我是指教我开柜子的方法
I mean, for the tip for the locker.
回见  再见
See you. Bye.
我从来没想过我会这么说
I never thought I'd say this,
但是我已经开始想念隔离区学校了
but I'm already starting to miss our Sector School.
人类就是野蛮人
Humans are savages,
无一例外  罗曼
Roman, every single one of them.
是吧
Right?
对  没错
Yeah. Right.
我宣誓忠实于美利坚合众国国旗
I pledge allegiance to the flag of the United of America,
忠实于她所代表的合众国
and to the republic, for which it stands,
苍天之下一个无可分割的国家
one nation, indivisible,
在这里  人人享有自由与正义
with liberty and justice for all.
好了
All right.
我将发给你们这个学期的课程表
I'll be passing out your syllabus for the semester.
自己留一份  然后往后传
Take one and pass it back.
据说他们有三个鸡鸡
Rumor is they have three penises.
小号  中号  还有超大号
Small, medium and extra large.
没错  她是泰勒  甜美  大姐大
Yep. Taylor. Sweet girl, braces.
记得中学时代吧
Remember in middle school?
她现在掌权了
Yeah, now she's in charge.
掌什么权
In charge of what?
所有一切
All of it.
你听说过奥特里安人
Hey, have you heard of an herb
可能在隔离区种了一种药草吗
the Atrians supposedly grow in the Sector?
好像叫"柏草"
Something called "Cyper"?
据说这种药草有魔力
It's, like, some miracle herb.
柏草  没听说过
Cyper? No.
不过你要是指大麻
But if it's herbs you seek,
说不定瘾君子的柜子里有
some of the stoners probably have some in their lockers.
你们吃我们的食物  穿我们的衣服
You eat our food, wear our clothes,
呼吸我们的空气  却不愿对我们的国旗宣誓
breathe our air,but you can't be bothered to pledge our flag?
我们不是地球公民
We're not citizens.
没错  你们是火星人
Oh, that's right. You're Martians.
实际上  火星人是火星来的
Well, technically, Martians are from Mars.
我们的星球要高级多了
We're from a far superior planet.
你说什么  怪胎
What did you say to me, freak?
到此为止
Hey, that's enough!
奥特里安人不需要对国旗宣誓
Atrians are not required to pledge to the flag.
振作点
Cheer up.
你们的自由和正义  我们不会夺去
You get to keep liberty and justice all to yourself.
打开秋季学期日程表
Open up the fall semester calendar.
有些重要活动
We have some events coming up.
诺克斯  你一直极力主张奥特里安人
Nox, you've been the Atrians' most vocal advocate
与地球人享有平等权利
for equal rights.
你真的认为会有这么一天
Did you think this day would ever come?
我一直充满希望
I never lost that hope.
这个项目是迈向种族统一的第一步
This program is the first step toward unifying our races.
我无比自豪
And I couldn't be prouder
因为我自己的孩子参与了这历史性的一刻
that my own children are part of history in the making.
-谢谢  先生  -谢谢你
- Thank you, gentlemen. - Thank you.
奥特里安隔离区 - 东门
这是奥特里安七人组  我们过去
It's the Atrian Seven! Let's go!
感觉怎样
Hey. How did it go?
很好  跟我们在隔离区受到的凌辱相比
Excellent. We've been far too insulated in the Sector
这里的人们善良多了
from just how kind and compassionate these people can be.
你哥现在已经
Your brother has mastered
深谙地球人的幽默艺术了
the earthly art of sarcasm with relative ease.
说来听听  如果我有幸交到人类朋友
Tell me about it. If I have any chance of making friends,
我就装作不认识他了
I'm gonna have to distance myself from him.
为什么要跟人类做朋友
Why do you want to be friends with them?
人类比咱们有趣多了
Humans are so much more colorful.
抱歉  但今天哪里有趣了
I'm sorry. What about today was colorful?
是武装警卫还是抗议者
Was it the armed guards or the protestors?
还是  我知道了  是憎恨我们的同学
Or...? Oh, wait. I know. The human kids that hate us.
他们只是还不了解我们
They just don't know us yet.
[外星语]
玛雅  讲英文
Maia, English.
你们是去那里学习  不是交朋友的
You're there to learn, not to make friends.
明天又是新的一天
Well, tomorrow's a new day.
你女儿自己会解释
Your daughter will tell you exactly why
她为什么咽不下虾球捞面
she's not devouring that shrimp lo mein.
没什么
It's nothing.
我今天一直在想那个躲在棚屋里的男孩
I just... was thinking a lot about that boy in the shed today.
想他什么
What about him?
想如果他没有要保护我
About how, if he hadn't tried to protect me,
现在应该还活着
he'd still be alive.
不是所有人都能获救  宝贝
Not everyone can be saved, baby.
有时  要顾全大局
Sometimes... there's a greater plan at work.
用餐愉快
Enjoy your meal.
下午好  奥特里安人
Good afternoon, Atrian.
你的午餐选择为爆米花蛋糕
Your lunch option is puffed rice cake.
你要鸡肉味  牛肉味  还是胡萝卜味
Would you like chicken-flavored, beef or carrot?
用餐愉快
Enjoy your meal.
你叫埃默里  对吧
It's Emery, right?
你住在伍德格伦
You live over on Woodglen?
-是的  -手机拿出来
- Yeah. - Let me see your phone.
我们要在这个废弃农舍开派对
There's a party at this abandoned farmhouse.
你也来吧
You should come.
我可以带卢卡斯吗
Can I bring Lukas?
当然  如果你们俩是一对的话
Sure, yeah, if you guys are, like, a package deal.
-我们是朋友  -好
- We're friends. - Oh, good.
因为格雷森不确定
Because Grayson wasn't sure.
格雷森要约我吗
Grayson... was... asking?
我来跟你换班
I am relieving you of duties.
好  你来得刚好
Yes, yes, and you are just in time.
那个大姐大要做什么
So, what did that fembot want?
你怎么会受到邀请  小埃
How did you manage this, Em?
是她邀请我的  我们俩
She invited me. Or us.
她肯定爱上你了  卢克
I think she's got a crush on you, Luke.
不错啊  小埃  你真会哄人开心
That's cute, Em. That was real cute.
这是你的才能吧  很好
Was that your material? Great.
好
Okay.
这是你的社团
This is your club?
是的
Yeah.
就是去本地的医院
You go to local hospitals,
陪病人画画  做剪贴
spend time with patients, painting, scrapbooking,
诸如此类
that sort of thing.
我觉得很抚慰人心
I found it really comforting.
你去年是社团成员
You were in the club last year?
不是  我当时是病人
No. I was a patient.
过去四年由于免疫缺陷
I spent the last four years in the hospital
我一直在住院
because of an immune deficiency.
那你更喜欢哪个
So, what did you prefer?
画画还是做剪贴
The painting or the scrapbooking?
做剪贴
The scrapbooking.
谁都可以参加吗
So anyone can join?
要占用很多课余时间
It's a lot of after-school hours,
你们有宵禁令  也不准出隔离区
and with your curfew and not being permitted outside the Sector...
我是说  不准私自出隔离区
I mean, your Sector without permission,
不用说了  我懂  我懂
No, I understand. I understand.
我的记忆存储在另一台电脑上
My memories are stored on a separate computer anyway,
我可能不适合做剪贴
so I probably wouldn't be good at scrapbooking.
开玩笑的
Joking.
还是谢了
Thanks anyway.
喜欢搭讪地球女孩啊  歪星人
You like talking to our girls there, Tattie?
很漂亮吧
You think they're pretty?
我是想加入她的社团  她没同意
I was interested in joining her club, but she wouldn't have me.
不用替我遗憾
No, don't feel bad.
还好没成
It's just as well.
我也没什么艺术骨头[细胞]
I don't have an artistic bone in my body.
你全身上下有骨头吗
Do you have any bones in your body?
说得好
Good point.
我们的骨骼系统
Our, uh, skeletal system is made up
由一万条蜈蚣手拉手组成
of 10,000 centipedes holding hands,
不过那是奥特里安人的145号秘密
but that's Atrian secret number 145.
你怎么知道的
How do you know that?
-一切都好吗  罗曼  -没事
- Everything okay, Roman? - Yeah.
我们只是在互相了解
We're just getting to know each other.
我不在乎你爸爸是奥特里安人里的大人物
I don't care that your dad is some big Atrian honcho.
你在这里就要遵守我们的规矩
You play by our rules here.
明白了吗  怪胎
Got it, freak?
-得了吧  -泰瑞
- Come on... - Teri.
明白了
Got it.
等等  他们因为你跟
So, wait, they were pissed
奥特里安人说话而大发雷霆
because you talked to an Atrian?
我想这有点像是所有人最糟糕的噩梦
I mean, I guess it sort of is everyone's worst nightmare.
什么
What is?
人类和奥特里安之间的恋爱倾向
The notion of the human-Atrian hookup.
"恋爱"  我们在谈论
A "Hookup." Okay, we were talking about
绘画和剪贴
painting and scrapbooking.
恋爱都是这样开始的
That's how it begins.
我认为得给你找一个新的爱好
I think we need to find you a new hobby,
像是吹制玻璃  肚皮舞也可以
like glassblowing, maybe belly dancing.
比如...
Something like...
这些是什么
What are these?
出院表
Discharge forms.
你要回家了
You're going home?
不回来了
For good?
没错
Yeah.
星期二
Tuesday.
你没有跟我说这件事
A-And you didn't tell me?
化疗不管用
The chemo isn't working.
而且找到一个匹配的骨髓
And finding a bone marrow match
也需耗费数年
could take years.
那么你为什么要回家
So, then why are you going home?
我有贫血症
I'm anemic.
我每隔一周就会得肺炎
I'm getting pneumonia every other week.
我的血小板数目不停减少
My platelet count keeps dropping.
小朱  你不能就这么放弃了
Jules, you're not giving up.
这不是放弃的问题
It's not about giving up.
我一点都不在乎做检查
I don't even care about the poking
针扎还有呕吐
and the prodding and the puking.
我再也承受不了的是
What I can't take anymore
看见我的父母重燃希望
is seeing my parents get their hopes up...
却因为一次次的
only to have them dashed
全血细胞数目测试结果而破灭
one lousy CBC test after another.
他们允许你外出一小时的  对吧
They'll let you out for an hour, right?
怎么了  我们要去哪里
Why? Where are we going?
你确定你知道这个柏草长什么样吗
And you're sure you know what this cyper herb looks like?
-确定  -很好
- Yes. - Good.
因为我爸绝对不会轻饶我偷了他的通行证
'Cause my dad will kill me for stealing his access badge.
隔离区执法队
雷·怀特希尔
[外星语]
要手镯吗
Ah. Bracelets?
-好吧  我买三个  -不用了  谢谢
- Okay. I'll take three. - Oh, no, thank you.
-朱莉娅  不要买  -不用了  谢谢
- Julia, no. - No, thank you.
看看这是谁来了
What do we have here?
你们这些孩子知道不该来到这里的
You kids know you're not supposed to be here.
你有柏草吗
Do you have any cyper?
柏草
Cyper.
跟我来
Right here.
走吧
Come on.
[外星语]
一级防范禁闭
Lockdown.
此隔离区现在正在封锁
This Sector is now under lockdown!
快走  快走  快走
Come on, come on, come on!
-跟我走  -好的
- Let's go. - Okay.
一级防范禁闭
Lockdown!
我们在这里是安全的
We'll be safe up here.
小朱  你还好吗
Jules, you okay?
你在跟我开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
这真是太不可思议了
That was amazing.
你们俩来这里干什么
What are you guys doing here?
我们来找你们的柏草
We came for your cyper.
那你为什么不直接说就好了
Well, why didn't you just say so?
我猜它的疗效已经不再只是我们族群之间的秘密了
I guess its curative powers are no longer just our secret.
快过来
Come on.
我们从太空船上偷偷带了一些种子进隔离区
We smuggled some seeds into the Sector from our ship.
-这是什么地方  -我和我爸一起建造的
- What is this place? - My dad and I built it.
这儿有点像是我们的私人避难所
It's kind of like our own private sanctuary.
就在这里
Here it is.
天哪  这里有好多柏草
Wow, there's so much of it!
想拿多少就拿多少吧
Take as much as you'd like.
这真的是柏草吗
Is this really cyper?
没错
Yep.
货真价实
It's really cyper.
或者是按照你们的说法
Or, as you call it,
藏红花
saffron.
Saffron?
我们是这么看待它的
Well, it's our own version of it.
我们用它来做饭
We use it for cooking.
但是一些胆大的警卫吹嘘我们香料的神奇功效
But some enterprising guards have made a good amount of cash
卖给在隔离区外容易上当受骗的人类
selling our spice's magic remedy to...
赚了一大票
gullible humans outside the Sector.
这总是值得一试的
It was worth a shot.
你有一个患病的朋友吗
Do you... have a sick friend?
我没有
Um, I don't.
她有
She does.
对不起
I'm sorry.
这也不能算是一无所获
Hey, this wasn't a total loss.
至少我看到了这个地方
At least I got to see this place.
我对于奥特里安人的所有东西都很喜欢
I'm... obsessed with all things Atrian.
你冷得直发抖  给你
You're shivering. Here.
谢谢
Thanks.
真有骑士风度
So chivalrous.
城市从这上面看好美
City looks beautiful from up here.
你这条疤怎么来的
How did you get that scar?
这是很久之前的事了
It... it happened a long time ago.
我们抵达地球的那天
On Arrival Day.
当时在那个棚屋的人是你  对吧
That was you i-in the shed, wasn't it?
你一直都知道
You knew this whole time.
怎么知道的
How?
我在学校见到你的那一瞬间
The moment I saw you at school,
我就产生了这种
I had this...
对冷掉的意大利面条的异乎寻常的渴望
bizarre craving for cold spaghetti.
但是我很确定你已经死了
But I was sure you were dead.
我亲眼看到他们射死了你
I saw them carry you away.
是差点死掉
I came close.
我的一个心脏确实停跳了
One of my hearts actually stopped beating
几分钟
for a few minutes.
幸好我还有备用的
Luckily, i have a backup.
我一直没机会谢谢你当年救了我
I never got to thank you... for saving my life.
我当时才六岁
I-I was six.
我没帮到你什么
I hardly did anything.
别人冷酷无情时  你却宽容相待
You were kind... when everyone else was cruel.
这对我意义重大
That's something.
宵禁警告
Curfew warning...
十分钟后就宵禁了  你们该走了
Curfew starts in ten minutes; you guys should go.
宵禁警告  十...
Curfew warning: ten...
我不敢相信当年棚屋里的男孩就是他
I can't believe that was him, the boy from the shed.
不过他显然已经长大了
But, clearly, he's no longer just a boy.
朱莉娅
Julia...
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你在隔离区肯定
Come on, you got to have a boyfriend
有男友吧
back in the Sector, right?
我真没有
No. There's nobody.
谁会想到奥特里安人能这么性感
Who knew an Atrian could be so sexy?
你是校园里的话题女王
You're the talk of the school.
不过别告诉你的朋友泰瑞
Oh, but don't tell your friend Teri, though,
因为我们觉得她可能会咬人
'cause we think she might bite.
我该去上课了
I should get to class.
你去哪里  你去哪里
Where you going? Where you going?
跟我说说
Hey, tell me something,
有关歪星人的传言是真的吗
is it true what they say about Tatties?
别碰我
Oh... Don't!
你性子还挺烈的嘛
Well, you're kind of a feisty one, aren't you?
-别碰我  -喂  你
- Stop it! - Hey! Hey!
离她远点
Leave her alone.
你非得碍我的事是吧
You just can't seem to get out of my way, can you?
她是我妹妹
That's my sister.
那好
Okay.
罗曼
Roman!
-来人啊  -放开他
- Help! - Get off him!
放开他
Hey, get off him!
谁来帮帮他
Somebody help him!
别打了  别再打了
Hey! Hey, break it up. Break it up.
滚吧
Get out of here!
滚回你的垃圾星球去吧
Go back to your own damn planet!
快让他滚
Hey, get him the hell out of here!
我观察你很久了  罗曼
I've been watching you for a long time, Roman.
我和你父亲一起
I worked closely with your father
促成了这个项目
to help build this program.
你要是不想让它失败
Unless you want to see it fail,
就别像个野兽一样为所欲为
you have to stop acting like an animal.
他攻击我妹妹  我却成了野兽
He assaulted my sister, and I'm the animal?
要是这种事再次发生
This happens again,
他们就会把你交给军医
they'll hand you over to military doctors to have
用你的睾丸做实验
your testicles put in a jar and studied.
你不想这样吧
You don't want that.
我也不想这样
I don't want that.
我的睾丸也绝对不想
And my testicles definitely don't want that.
我一向倾力保护我的投入
I always protect my investments.
但前提是他们有生存能力
That is, until they lose their viability.
罗曼
Roman.
今晚你会来吧
You're coming tonight, right?
没错  格雷森  你会看到她的
Yes, Grayson, you're gonna see her tonight.
拜托  能洒脱一点吗
God. Attempt to be cool.
连像埃默里这样的社交新人
Even social newbies like Emery
都还是喜欢那些暗恋者不要太过主动
still like a little cool with their drool.
C区清人检查
Quadrant C cleared for inspection.
不用你管  泰瑞
Stay out of it, Teri.
就算你能闯进他们的烂派对
Even if you can get out to crash their lame party,
你也不可能在宵禁之前赶回来
you'll never get back in time to make curfew.
不试试看怎么知道
Maybe, maybe not.
我们得给他们点颜色看看
But we need to send a message, all right?
不能让今天罗曼的事再重演
What happened to Roman today can never happen again.
都开始穿高跟鞋了
High heels now?
要去约会了
It's the beginning of the end.
去参加派对而已
No, it's a party.
多加小心
You'll be careful?
一向如此
Always.
玩得开心点
Have fun.
你该好好放松一下了
You deserve it.
我要去隔离区了
I'm out of here. Off to the Sectoec
老爸再见
Bye, Dad!
你想念它吗
Do you ever miss it?
想念什么
What?
奥特里安吗
Atria?
当然
Of course.
没有一天不想
Every day.
但是
But...
如今这里才是我们的家
this is our home now.
武装守卫
Armed guards,
强制宵禁  还有铁丝网
mandatory curfew and barbed wire.
我印象里的家可不是这样的
It's not exactly my idea of home.
不会一成不变的
It won't be like that forever.
老爸  他们
Dad, they're...
他们不会平等对待我们的
they're never gonna treat us like equals.
你们这代人会消除隔阂的
You know, your generation can bridge the gap.
有隔阂也是他们造成的
A gap they created.
我不是说这一切能立马实现
I-I'm not saying it's gonna happen tomorrow.
这需要时间
These things take time.
但我相信他们
But I have faith in them.
就如同我相信你一样
Just like I have faith in you.
你跟其他人不一样
You're not like the rest.
我看不到希望
I just don't see it.
我们明天再接着种吧
We'll finish this planting tomorrow.
怎么了  泰瑞
What do you want, Teri?
我看到你昨晚
I saw you last night
和那个叫埃默里的女孩在一起
with that girl Emery.
我只是帮她脱离困境
I was keeping her out of trouble.
我不明白你为什么要费心和他们来往
I don't know why you even bother making connections with them.
他们很快就会被隔离起来了
Soon, they're gonna be the ones behind these walls.
你这话是什么意思
What are you talking about?
我妈和其他人
Just something my mother
在他们的周一聚会上这么说的
and the rest of the Trags talk about in their Monday meeting.
无意冒犯  泰瑞  但你妈屁也不懂
No offense, Teri, but your mother's an idiot.
顺便说一句
Oh, and by the way,
德雷克他们去找那个埃里克了
Drake and them went after that kid Eric.
一级防范禁闭  2200小时
Lockdown, 2200 hours.
我想要溜出去
I'm looking for the path to Hades.
你不是诺克斯的儿子吗
Aren't you Nox's son?
你一定是认错人了
You must be confused.
能帮我吗
Can you help?
就像我跟你朋友说的那样
As I told your friends,
在标记重新启动之前
you've got three hours
你只有三个小时
before the signal reactivates.
B区8号走廊
Zone B. Corridor 8.
找到那盏坏掉的灯
Look for the broken light.
正下方有一块假墙板
Directly beneath, there's a false panel.
好了
Okay.
我不得不动粗才从一个新生那里搞到
I had to strong-arm a freshman to get the last
最后一点蓝色潘趣
of the blue punch.
谢谢
Thanks.
干杯
Cheers.
你还好吧
You all right?
当然了
Yeah. Sure.
你看上去有些心不在焉
You just seem a little distracted.
这一切对我来说
This is all just...
太新鲜了
pretty new to me.
要试着放松  没人会说你闲话的
Just try to relax. You're not being judged.
这里的大多数人都自恋得很
Most people here are too self-obsessed
才不会关心别人呢
to care about anyone else.
大家快来看啊
Hey! You guys got to see this!
看看他们对布洛克干了什么
Look what someone did to Brock!
谁干的
Who did this?
Who did this?!
我们只想谈谈
We just want to have a little talk.
好吧
All right.
今晚得做个了结
This ends tonight.
只此一次  我同意
For once, we agree.
我们受够了
We're sick of it!
你们这群人每天都来找我们麻烦
You guys messing with us every day!
都结束了  如果你们再纠缠我们
It's done! It's over! This is what's gonna happen
这就是你们的下场  听明白了吗
if you keep messing with us, you hear me?!
住手
Hey! Come on!
罗曼  你来干什么
Roman, what are you doing here?
你知道他们发现你们出了隔离区
Do you know what they'd do to you
会拿你怎么样吗
if they found you outside the Sector?
你应该和我一条战线
You should be fighting alongside of me
而不是和我对着干
instead of against me!
警察
Cops!
快跑
Come on!
罗曼  罗曼  罗...
Roman. Roman! Ro...!
-你没事吧  -埃默里  快走
- Are you okay? - Emery, come on!
快来  罗曼  上车
Come on! Roman, get in!
你疯了吗  埃默里  别管他了
Are you nuts? Come on, Emery, just leave him!
警察来了怎么办
But what about the cops?!
那是他的问题  不关我们的事  快走
His problem, not ours! Come on!
埃默里  你要干什么  走啊
Emery, what are you doing? Let's go!
-埃默里  -格雷森  我们必须离开
- Emery! - Grayson, we got to go right now.
罗曼  快跑  跑比较快
Roman, come on. We'll be faster on foot.
-我们不能丢下她  -当然可以
- We can't just leave her! - Yes, we can, man!
她简直是个疯子
She's a total freak!
伙计  她选择了那个歪星人
Dude, she chose the Tattie over you.
认了吧
Own it.
快点  我们走
Come on! Let's go!
你还好吗
Are you okay?
除了刚才社交自杀了一把
Other than having possibly just committed social suicide?
社交自杀  指躲开人群  避免社交活动
还好
Sure.
你呢
You okay?
真好笑
You know, it's funny.
这么多年来我父亲一直在教我
All these years, my dad has taught me
那被称道的所谓"人性"
about this vaunted thing called "Humanity,"
从定义上来说  那是我们
something that, by definition,
不可能拥有的
we could never possess.
但是...
But...
和你们人类接触了几天之后
after spending just a few days amongst your kind...
我弄不明白"人性"这个概念了
this concept of "Humanity" doesn't seem so clear to me.
不是的  世上还是有很多好人的
No. There are a lot of good people out there.
是吗
Yeah?
我只遇见过一个
Well, I've only met one.
你不必害怕
You don't have to be afraid.
对不起
Sorry.
是我妈
It's my mom.
我一会儿就到家
I'll be home soon.
好的  我正在路上
O-Okay. I'm on my way.
是...朱莉娅
It's... Julia.
我得走了
I have to go.
我明白
I understand.
继续往前直走
If you keep walking straight,
你就会找到回隔离区的路
you'll find the road to the Sector.
谢谢你
Thanks.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我得走了
I have to go.
泰瑞
Teri.
几小时前你和罗曼在一起
You were with Roman a few hours ago.
你知道他现在在哪里吗  都快宵禁了
Do you know where he is? It's almost curfew.
泰瑞
Teri?
你怎么能让我儿子出去
How could you let my son go out there?
先生们  出什么事了
Is there a problem here, gentlemen?
没事
No, we're good.
离开桌子  让我看到你们的手
Step away from the table. Let me see your hands.
那是什么
What's that?
这可不行  威布尔
Not good, Weeble.
放下武器
Drop your weapon!
威布尔  不要
Weeble, no!
有人中枪
Man down!
怀特希尔指挥官
Commander Whitehill!
雷
Ray!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
星恋